beaverbrooks.co.uk 2011-12-09

# Beaverbrooks Privacy Policy - Beaverbrooks The Jewellers

The following statement explains Beaverbrooks policy regarding the personal information we collect about you.

  1. **Statement of intent**  
From time to time, you will be asked to submit personal information about yourself (e.g. name and email address etc) in order to receive or use services on our website. Such services include newsletters, diary reminders and email bulletins. 

By entering your details in the fields requested, you enable **Beaverbrooks the Jewellers Ltd** and its service providers to provide you with the services you select. Whenever you provide such personal information, we will treat that information in accordance with this policy. Our services are designed to give you the information that you want to receive. **Beaverbrooks the Jewellers Ltd** will act in accordance with current legislation and aim to meet current Internet best practice.

  2. **Information on visitors**  
During the course of any visit to **Beaverbrooks the Jewellers Ltd** website, the pages you see, along with something called a cookie, are downloaded to your computer. Most, if not all, websites do this, because cookies allow the website publisher to do useful things like find out whether the computer (and probably its user) has visited the site before. This is done on a repeat visit by checking to see, and finding, the cookie left there on the last visit. 

Any information that is supplied by cookies can help us to provide you with a better service and assists us to analyse the profile of our visitors.

Both the cookies and the embedded code provide non-personal statistical information about visits to pages on the site, the duration of individual page view, paths taken by visitors through the site, data on visitors' screen settings and other general information. **Beaverbrooks the Jewellers Ltd** use this type of information, as with that obtained from other cookies used on the site, to help it improve the services to its users.

The Beaverbrooks website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service, which sets a cookie in order for us understand how visitors are using our site. Google Analytics collects the information anonymously and we use this information to help us improve our website.

**If you wish to disable these cookies you can opt-out using the below link**

<http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en-GB>

  3. **What is a cookie?**  
When you enter a site your computer will automatically be issued with a cookie. Cookies are text files that identify your computer to our server. Cookies in themselves do not identify the individual user, just the computer used. Many sites do this whenever a user visits their site in order to track traffic flows. 

Cookies themselves only record those areas of the site that have been visited by the computer in question, and for how long. Users have the opportunity to set their computers to accept all cookies, to notify them when a cookie is issued, or not to receive cookies at any time. The last of these, of course, means that certain personalised services cannot then be provided to that user.

If you do want to delete or control the use of Cookies you can find out how by following this link [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/ "How to Delete or Control Cookies")

NB: Even if you haven't set your computer to reject cookies you can still browse our site anonymously until such time as you register for **Beaverbrooks the Jewellers Ltd** services.

  4. **Use and storage of your personal information**  
When you supply any personal information to **Beaverbrooks the Jewellers Ltd** (e.g. when ordering products or services) we have legal obligations towards you in the way we deal with that data. We must collect the information fairly and tell you if we want to pass the information on to anyone else. In general, any information you provide to **Beaverbrooks the Jewellers Ltd** will only be used within **Beaverbrooks the Jewellers Ltd**. It will never be supplied to anyone outside **Beaverbrooks the Jewellers Ltd** without first obtaining your consent, unless we are obliged or permitted by law to disclose it. Also, if you post or send offensive or inappropriate content anywhere on or to **Beaverbrooks the Jewellers Ltd** and **Beaverbrooks the Jewellers Ltd** considers such behaviour to be serious and/or repeated, **Beaverbrooks the Jewellers Ltd** can use whatever information that is available to it about you to stop such behaviour. This may include informing relevant third parties such as your employer, school or e-mail provider about the content and your behaviour. 

We will hold your personal information on our systems for as long as you use the service you have requested, and remove it in the event that the purpose has been met, or, in the case of a personalised service, such as online billing, you no longer wish to continue your registration as a personalised user. Where personal information is held for people who are not yet registered but have taken part in other **Beaverbrooks the Jewellers Ltd** services (e.g. information requests), that information will be held only as long as necessary to ensure that the service is run smoothly. We will ensure that all personal information supplied is held securely, in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998.

  5. **Access to your personal information**  
You have the right to request a copy of the personal information **Beaverbrooks the Jewellers Ltd** holds about you and to have any inaccuracies corrected. Please address requests to:-

Website Manager  
Beaverbrooks the Jewellers Ltd  
Adele House  
Park Road  
Lytham St. Annes  
Lancashire  
FY8 1RE

  6. **Users 16 and under**  
If you are aged 16 or under, please get your parent/guardian's permission beforehand whenever you provide personal information to **Beaverbrooks the Jewellers Ltd** website. Users without this consent are not allowed to provide us with personal information.
  7. **Use of pixels**  
Beaverbrooks uses pixels, or transparent GIF files, to help manage online advertising. These GIF files are provided by our ad management partner, DoubleClick. These files enable DoubleClick to recognize a unique cookie on your Web browser, which in turn enables us to learn which advertisements bring users to our website. The cookie was placed by us, or by another advertiser who works with DoubleClick. With both cookies and Spotlight technology, the information that we collect and share is anonymous and not personally identifiable. It does not contain your name, address, telephone number, or email address. 

For more information about DoubleClick, including information about how to opt out of these technologies, go to <http://www.doubleclick.net/us/corporate/privacy>.
